# 一般人不知道 以为就是一块东坡肉
Most people don’t know. They think it’s just a piece of Dongpo Pork
# 但是没想到 一下嘴
But they didn't expect, when you put it in your mouth
# 用最便宜的食材
Use the cheapest ingredients
# 做出你吃不起的样子
Make something look like you can't afford it
# 原料是冬瓜
The ingredient is winter melon
# 猴头菇 素肉 鸡蛋
Hericium edodes, vegetarian meat, and eggs
# 这是猴头菇 魏刚强提前给切好了的
This is hericium edodes. Wei Gangqiang cut it in advance
# 这全是素的啊师父 没肉啊
This is all vegetable, Master, no meat?
# 您看见没有 这冬瓜
Did you see this winter melon
# 切成一方块 然后两边一片这儿一片
Cut into a cube and then cut on both sides
# 然后你看 打这么一个方块就出来了
Then you see, you can make it to a cube
# 其实很简单
it's actually very easy
# 一刀唰一剔 一刀一剔
Cut and then get rid of this middle part
# 这叫什么菜名 金刚火方
What is the name of this dish? King Kong “Meat Cube”
# 这是功德林的代表名菜
This is one of the representative dish of Gong De Lin
# 这个您看
Look at this
# 这猴头菇先拿水加点味煮它一下
This Hericium edodes first need to boil in the water
# 猴头菇必须得出水 鲜的也得出水
You need to boil hericium edodes, even for fresh ones
# 出水以后去去它那个味道
After boiling, it can get rid of its (earthy) taste
# 小魏你看 为什么要剁啊你知道么
Xiao wei, see? Why chop? Do you know?
# 剁完之后它就有黏性了 否则它散
It will become sticky after chopping, otherwise it is loose
# 这就行了
That's it
# 这个素肉是什么成分呢
What is the ingredient of this vegetarian meat?
# 大豆做的蛋白
Soy protein
# 这个东西多点少点都没关系
It doesn't matter how much you use it
# 这馅儿准备好了 调味了
The stuffing is ready and let's season
# 这个一个蛋黄 其实有半个蛋黄就足够
This one egg yolk, actually half is enough
# 这是俗家的素席
This is a Buddhist banquet
# 加点盐 放放放
Add some salt
# 胡椒粉
pepper
# 行了
Enough
# 来点粉子
Some starch
# 摔拌
Beat and mix
# 原料拍粉
Put some starch on the ingredient
# 干粉子 为了叫它抓住
Dry starch, in order to make it easy to grab (other ingredients)
# 粉子它能拿劲儿啊 能粘
Starch can grab (other ingredients) and be sticky
# 你看 这基本粉子就铺匀了
You see, the starch is evenly spread
# 瓤馅了得
Stuffing now
# 把馅儿抹在冬瓜上
Spread the stuffing on the winter melon
# 这槽好粘东西啊 要不然粘不上
This slot make it easy to stick stuffing, otherwise it won’t stick
# 它有附着力 它能黏合
# 上能抓住劲儿
It has adhesion, so it can stick on and grab (other ingredients)
# 这点馅儿正合适
This stuffing is right
# 怎么这么会弄啊 没毛病师父
Why are you so good at making this? No problem, Master
# 抹蛋清 光滑
Spread the egg whites, smooth
# 封住它的平面
Seal its surface
# 来点老抽吧小魏 来啦
Some soy sauce, Xiao Wei, here
# 像五花三层的样
Like pork belly with three layers
# 你看 层出来了
You see, the layers come out
# 大爷 你看
Da Ye, look
# 抹上点老抽
Spread some dark soy sauce
# 这有点像我们的扣肉一样
This is a bit like our meat
# 抹点老抽下锅炸的时候
# 上色
Spread some dark soy sauce for coloring when frying
# 来 师父 笊篱
Here, master, sieve
# 差不多了 六到七成油温
It's almost 60% to 70% oil temperature (180 – 210 C)
# 先不能攉拢啊 定型
# 上色
Shouldn’t move it around. Fix the shape first and for coloring
# 漂亮啊 五花肉出来了
It’s pretty. Pork belly is here.
# 没问题
No problem
# 肉方出来了
You can see the “meat cube” now
# 这还是 不错的啊 妥妥的
This is still good.
# 炒汁儿了开始
Start making sauce
# 来点油 葱姜大料 料酒
Some oil, green onion and ginger, cooking wine
# 香菇水
Soaked mushroom water
# 酱油
Soy sauce
# 再加点水啊 大爷
Add some water, Da Ye.
# 胡椒粉 很简单
Pepper powder, very simple
# 稍微点点儿糖 来点蚝油 香菇
A little sugar, some oyster sauce, shiitake mushrooms
# 好 把这葱姜香味熬出来
OK, boil out the aroma of green onion and ginger
# 大爷您看
Da Ye, see
# 葱姜香菇熬的水 还有大料
The water boiled with green onion, ginger, mushrooms and star anise
# 熬好了以后我们就灌到
After it's cooked, we pour it on
# 炸好的冬瓜方
Fried winter melon cube
# 半个小时就差不多了
It's almost half an hour
# 盖盖儿 水够足么 够足
Cover it. Is the water enough? Enough
# 下一步我们配点油菜吧
Let's prepare some bok choy next
# 削好了以后 胡萝卜头儿您看
After cutting it, look at this carrot "head"
# 插进去就行了 这叫鹦鹉菜心
Just plug it in. This is called "Parrot Bok Choy"
# 水边加点盐 加点糖
Add some salt to the water and some sugar
# 提鲜 还有去涩的作用
Improve taste and remove astringency
# 我们再滴一点明油 翠绿光亮
Let's add a little bit of oil, to make it bright green
# 稍微一烫
Slightly blanch it
# 好了
Good
# 关火
Turn off heat
# 小魏这重要任务交给你了 半个小时
Xiao Wei, this important task is on your shoulder.For half an hour
# 师父我给你出盘
Master, let me help you take it out
# 出锅喽
Out of the pot
# 可以了啊 把这葱姜拣出去
Okay, pick out the green onion and ginger
# 取其精华 去其糟粕 本味
Leave the essence inside and remove the dross
# （原汤倒进锅里）
(Pour the original soup into the pot)
# 别着急慢慢的来
Be patient, do it slowly
# 你看 走起
See, there we go
# 你行啊你
Not bad!
# 出水见芙蓉
Like a lotus coming out of the water
# 像个五花肉
Like a pork belly
# 跟五花肉一样 行了
Same as pork belly. Good
# 让它似开非开 然后勾芡
Make it look open but not fully open, and then make slurry
# 再淋点颜色 老抽
More color, soy sauce
# 蒸的原汤 勾点芡
Original soup from steaming, make the slurry
# 小火 勾芡要用小火
Low heat, use low heat to make the slurry
# 为什么用小火啊 出来芡亮
Why use a low heat? The slurry will be shinny
# 这回行了 好
Now looks good. Good
# 淋点油
Some oil
# 明油 这是粤菜的打蚝油芡的手法
Oil, this is the way to make oyster sauce slurry in Cantonese cuisine
# 油在
Oil should be
# 这四周这汁儿划圆了它
Around the cube. Draw a circle
# 小魏把菜心拿来
Xiao Wei, bring the bok choy
# 九个 一边三棵
Nine, three on each side
# 摆一圈就行了 齐活
Just arrange them in a circle, done.
# 金刚火方 漂亮
King Kong Winter Melon Cube. Beautiful!
# 这菜我看了N多遍了
I have watched this dish N times
# 但是我一次都没吃过
But I never tried it
# 大爷 您老先尝 谢谢
Da Ye, you try it first. Thank you
# 好吃 猛一眼看
Delicious, take a quick look
# 就跟
like
# 这冬瓜 看似好像硬点
This winter melon seems a bit too hard
# 但是它不能软了
But it can't be softer
# 再软肉馅和冬瓜就分离了
If so, the “meat” and winter melon are separated
# 它必须得拿住它
It has to grab it
# 甜咸适中 汁儿红芡儿亮
Moderately sweet and salty, bright red slurry
# 五花三层 你吃的是肥的
“Pork belly”, what you eat is “fat”
# 确实地道啊
Really authentic
# 一个普通的不起眼的食材
An ordinary ingredient
# 做出了一道大菜
Made a big dish
# 谢谢二伯 谢谢师父
Thank you Er Bai, thank you master
# 煲汤是把原材料搁在里边
Soup is to put the raw materials inside
# 慢慢的煲
Slowly cook
# 一次性成熟
then the dish is done.
# 吊汤就不一样
Broth is different
# 比如说我们吊清汤
For example, we make clear broth
# 吊完之后
After the broth is made
# 再进行清
You then make it clear
# 时间不一样
Time is different
# 吊汤是做菜用的
Broth is for cooking
# 煲汤是直接喝的
Soup, you can just have it after you made it
# 开水白菜从吊汤开始
Boiling cabbage starts from making broth
# 吊完汤以后呢
After the broth is made
# 提出来以后要把油撇干净
Skim off the oil after you take the broth out
# 用鸡臊子把汤给搞清
Use chicken broth to make it clear
# 白菜再用开水烫熟
Boil the cabbage in boiling water
# 捋齐 灌上清汤上锅一蒸
Make it tidy, pour the clear broth and steam it
# 就好了
It’s done
# 吊汤来讲呢又分为有白臊
In terms of broth, it is divided into white minced meat
# 有红臊
And Red minced meat
# 白臊是鸡胸肉来调
White minced meat is made from chicken breast
# 红臊有的汤是清真用的
Red minced meat is for halal dishes
# 茶色 再用白臊再臊一遍
Tea color, use white minced meat to clear it one more time
# 这样这汤又香又鲜
So this soup is fragrant and fresh
# 那双吊汤呢
What about the double broth
# 牛肉臊一遍鸡肉臊一遍
Use minced beef and minced chicken to clear
# 我们在撇沫子的时候
When we were skimming the scum
# 就感觉上撇干净了
It feels clean
# 但我们再用点凉水
But if we use some cold water
# 再把它炸一下
“Smash” it (make it cool down)
# 它一开锅以后
Once it's boiling again
# 还会产生一些浮沫
It will also produce some scum
# 再把沫子一清
Then you skim off the scum
# 这汤显得更加清
This soup looks clearer
# 它是分阶段的去进行腌制的
It needs to marinade in stages
# 比如说我们明天用
For example, we use it tomorrow
# 我们今天晚上加工出来
We make it tonight
# 搁冰箱第二天再用
Put in the refrigerator and use in the next day
# 这效果更好
This works better